Leonard 我在研究我们去加州大学伯克利分校
Leonard, I've been working on an opening joke
演讲要用的开场笑话
for our lecture at Berkeley.
笑话我爱听
Oh, I like to laugh.
除了你的 说吧
But say it anyway.
好的...
Okay, um...
对一名加州大学伯克利分校
What do you say to a graduate
物理系毕业的学生该说什么?
of the UC Berkeley physics department?
讽刺他们要去快餐店工作
配餐我要薯条
I'll have fries with that.
因为他的专业并没有教会他
Because his education hasn't prepared him
在科学领域工作所需要的知识
for a career in the sciences.
要知道 他们追着你们打的时候
You know, when they chase you out of there,
你只需要比Sheldon跑得快就行
you only have to run faster than Sheldon.
行李都准备好了吗?
Are you all set for your trip?
嗯 都准备好了
Yeah, I think so.
我给旧的PRK补了货
I just restocked the old PRK.
PRK是什么?
"PRK"?
公共厕所救急包
Public restroom kit.
一包在手 就不用为要去新的
Everything a boy needs for making pee pee
陌生厕所嘘嘘担心了
in new and strange places.
我实在看不出来带着装有厕纸
I don't see what's crazy about bringing a backpack
和免洗消毒液的背包有什么奇怪的
with your own toilet paper and Purell.
还有呢
Keep going.
还有橡皮手套 空气清新剂
And rubber gloves, uh, air freshener.
降噪耳机
Um, noise-cancelling headphones.
求救哨子
Oh, danger whistle.
呃...
Um...
胡椒喷剂
pepper spray.
一块多语言"有人"牌子
Ooh, a multi-language "occupied" sign.
再看看
Uh, let's see.
还有马桶垫 鞋套
We have seat protectors, uh, booties for my shoes,
夹鼻子用的晾衣夹
a clothespin for my nose.
还有长杆镜
Oh, and a mirror on a stick,
这样我就能确保隔壁厕所间的人
so I can make sure the person in the stall next to me
不是个变态了
isn't some kind of weirdo.
这样你还会担心伯克利有女生想抢走他吗?
You still worried some Berkeley girl is gonna steal him away?
当然 你以为是谁给他那个哨子的?
Yes, who do you think gave him the danger whistle?
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第八季第19集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 凤梨酥
校对: UU养了只狐狸叫查理
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
翻译: 酱油影 奥利奥 夏至未寒 UU养了只狐狸叫查理
你想玩个我发明的行车物理游戏
Would you like to play a physics car game I invented
"视觉不发现"吗?
called "I Can't Spy"?
这款游戏继承了"视觉大发现"的紧张刺激
It's all the nail-biting tension of "I Spy"
还增加了次原子微粒 可视光谱外
but the added fun of subatomic particles and waves
光波的乐趣
outside the visible spectrum.
只要这游戏
If it's half as much fun as
有"一乘以十的墙上第四瓶啤酒次方"一半有趣
"One Times Ten to the Fourth Bottles of Beer on the Wall,"
我就玩
I'm in.
从我开始
I'll begin.
我小小的眼睛发现不了...
Uh, I can't spy with my little eye...
有什么穿过了我们的身体?
something passing right through us.
我喝的那杯豆奶星冰乐
That soy Frappuccino I had.
你能好好玩游戏吗?
Will you please play the game?
我小小的眼睛发现不了
I can't spy with my little eye
有什么穿过了我们?
something passing right through us.
我不知道...
I don't know, um...
如果每秒每平方厘米的空间里
If 65 billion solar neutrinos pass
有650亿太阳中微子穿过
through a square centimeter every second,
由于这辆车的表面积
given the surface area of this car is
大约是6万平方厘米
about 60,000 square centimeters,
那答案是3.9乘以十的15次方个太阳中微子?
that means 3.9 times ten to the 15th solar neutrinos?
我不想玩了
I don't want to play anymore.
我们已经有段时间没有公路旅行了
We haven't been on a road trip in a while.
很有趣的
This is fun.
行了... 你赢了游戏
We get it... you won the game.
别炫耀了
Stop bragging.
听着 我们一起写了篇论文
No, listen, we wrote a paper together.
现在竟然被请去大学做讲座
Now we get to go to a university and talk about it?
那超厉害的
That's pretty cool.
我想是的
I suppose it is.
事实上 如果你想来点音乐庆祝一下
In fact, if you'd like to celebrate with a little music,
我完全同意
I'd be okay with that.
什么...?
What...?
这次公路旅行简直嗨翻了
This road trip just got crazy.
来点黑人放克音乐 白小子
Play that funky music, white boy.
你竟然知道这首歌
I'm surprised you know that reference.
什么歌?
What reference?
我在要卖掉的东西上都贴了贴纸
So, I put stickers on everything we're gonna sell.
只需要大家帮忙把东西搬到车道上
We just need help taking it all out to the driveway.
我可以负责定价吗?
Can I be in charge of pricing?
我经常去参加车库甩卖的
I've been going to garage sales my whole life.
信不信这条连裤袜我才花了五分钱?
Can you believe I got these pantyhose for a nickel?
好啊 Amy就负责定价和扮老
All right, Amy's in charge of pricing and being 75.
嘿 Penny 能帮我一起搬这个吗?
Hey, Penny, can you give me a hand with this?
当然
Sure.
我小时候就有个球桌的
Aw, we had one of these growing up.
我还一直玩呢
I used to play all the time.
是吗? 我喜欢打乒乓球
Oh, yeah? I love Ping-Pong.
我是说啤酒球
Oh, I meant beer pong.
Beer pong: 丢球进酒杯 不然就罚喝酒的游戏
我也有个球桌
I had a table, too,
但我没朋友 所以我只能一直发球
but I didn't have any friends, so all I did was serve.
你可以翻起一边的桌子 然后和它对打
You know, you can leave one side up and play against it.
要是我有朋友 他们也许就会告诉我
And if I had a friend, they might have told me that.
过来一下
Excuse me.
为什么这上面有贴纸?
Why is there a sticker on this?
TARDIS 科幻剧"神秘博士"中的时间机器和宇宙飞船
这是我买的神秘博士里的时间机器
It's my TARDIS from Doctor Who.
我打算搬回家的
I was planning on moving it in the house.
我觉得你刚才就已经自问自答了
I think you just answered your own question.
拜托 总有一天它的价值会翻倍
Come on, one day, this may double in value
能卖到我付出去的一半价格
and be worth half what I paid for it.
亲爱的 我们有很多事要做
Sweetie, we have a lot to do.
不用立刻决定要不要卖这个
We don't need to decide this right now.
只要你别固执己见一定要卖就好
Well, I guess as long as you're keeping an open mind.
当然
Of course.
所以... 他们要求
So... they're requesting
白小子放点放克音乐 对吧?
that the white boy play the funky music, yes?
对
Yes.
我们现在听的这个也是放克音乐?
And this music we're listening to right now is funky as well?
没错
Sure.
那我问你
Let me ask you this.
你觉得
Do you think
这首曲子就是白小子最后放的吗?
this song is the music the white boy ultimately plays?
也许是
It could be.
所以这就像是音乐里的罗素悖论
So it's like the musical equivalent of Russell's Paradox,
问题是由所有不包含自身的集合
the question of whether the set of all sets
所组成的集合是否包含自己?
that don't contain themselves as members contains itself?
- 没错  - 好吧...
- Exactly.  - Well...
那我讨厌它
then I hate it.
音乐应该是纯粹的享受
Music should just be fun.
开得挺快的
Making great time.
应该很早就能到那
Gonna be there pretty early.
我们的酒店房间能住吗?
Will our hotel room be ready?
可能不行
I doubt it.
你难道不担心在大厅里
Aren't you worried that sitting in the lobby
坐上很久可能会吸引
for a long period of time might attract the attention
酒店侦探的注意吗?
of the hotel detective?
要是的话
If we do,
我们就告诉他"一边去 看见没?"
we'll just tell him to "hit the bricks, see?"
听着有些强硬 但 好吧
Seems a little confrontational, but all right.
其实我们离天行者庄园
You know, we won't be very far
也不是很远
from Skywalker Ranch.
这倒不假
Oh, that's true.
但我们也进不去
It's not like we can get in there.
为什么?
Why not?
星战导演
我... 我觉得George Lucas把总部
I... I don't think George Lucas put his headquarters
建在一个偏僻的地方 应该不是希望有人拜访
in the middle of nowhere because he wanted people dropping in.
尤达的沼泽不也很偏僻
Yoda's swamp was in the middle of nowhere.
绝地尤达大师 "星球大战"人物
塔图因不也很偏僻
Tatooine was in the middle of nowhere.
塔图因: "星球大战" 中天行者家族的故乡行星
霍斯星球不也很偏僻
Hoth was in the middle of nowhere.
霍斯星球: "星球大战"中的冰雪世界
这是暗号 Leonard
That's code, Leonard.
他想要我们拜访
He wants us to drop in.
我们的确有这时间
We do have time.
我们可以顺便开到那看一眼
I mean, we could drive by and just look at it.
太好了! 啊...
Yes! Oh...
我是如此兴奋
I'm so excited.
简直无法自己
And I just can't hide it.
"哪怕即将失控 我也喜欢这样"
"I'm about to lose control, and I think I like it."
美国歌手P!nk的I'm So Excited中的歌词
你在瞎说什么?
What are you talking about?
那你们俩决定几时搬来住?
So when do you guys think you're gonna move in?
我们还在考虑要做多少改造
We're still figuring how much remodeling we want to do.
要在"现代品味"
It's tricky finding the right balance
和"犹太老妈破烂堆"
between "tasteful modern"
之间做到平衡很难
and "Jewish mother tchotchke crapfest."
决定要怎么处理时光机了吗?
Have you made a decision about the TARDIS?
我觉得把它改名为"大型英式洗手间" 应该卖得出去
I think I can sell it if we call it, "Big British Porta-Potty."
我们不卖它... 它是我的
We're not selling it... it's mine.
不能由你说了算
You can't just decide.
你我掰手腕决定怎么样?
How about I arm-wrestle you?
这不公平
That's not fair.
这好比我挑战你参加"性感裤子比赛"
It's like me challenging you to a sexy pants contest.
你们可以打乒乓决胜负
You could play Ping-Pong for it.
就这么办吧
I would do that.
这怎么公平了?
How is that fair?
你从小就有个乒乓球桌
You grew up with a table.
是没错 可我一般都用它作
Yes, but I mostly used it as a battlefield
变形金刚和霹雳猫之间的战场
in an ongoing war between the Transformers and the ThunderCats
争夺我在林子里找到的胸罩
for control of a bra I had found in the woods.
Bernadette 为了报Leonard逼我看
Bernadette, for every episode of Doctor Who
每一集"神秘博士"的仇
Leonard has made me sit through,
我来替你比赛
I will play on your behalf
然后把那时光机送回Gallifrey
and send that TARDIS back to Gallifrey,
Gallifrey "神秘博士"中时间领主们的母星
可恶 我居然知道这一点
where I hate that I know it belongs.
没错 Penny替我比赛
Yes, Penny plays for me.
这不公平... 她上半身肌肉很发达
That's not fair... she has upper body muscles.
老兄 咱可是圣斯克里帝中学
Dude, three-time Sanskriti School
名门贵族羽毛球的三界冠军
for Well-Born Boys badminton champion.
没错... 就这样 Raj替我比赛
That's right... okay, Raj can play for me.
哦 你们刚刚分别选了英雄
Ooh, you just chose champions.
感觉咱们就像在重演德国古老的
It's like we're reenacting the ancient German practice
- 格斗审判的传统  - 没错 还真像是
-  of trial by combat.  - Yeah, it's also like
"权力的游戏"里魔山和红毒蛇的那场决斗
when the Mountain fought the Red Viper in Game of Thrones.
Leonard还逼你看那个了?
Leonard makes you watch that, too?
没有 是我自己喜欢看
No, no, I like that show.
里面有龙 和激情片段
It's got dragons and people doing it.
那就这么定了
So it's settled.
神秘博士的时光机的命运将由一场
The fate of Doctor Who's TARDIS will be decided
受"权力的游戏"启发的生死决斗决定
by a Game of Thrones inspired death-match on the battlefield
场地是变形金刚大战霹雳猫的战场
of ThunderCats versus Transformers.
那胸罩还在的话 我愿意花5分钱买
If you still have that bra, I'll give you a nickel for it.
这就到了
There it is.
只是扇大门
It's just a gate.
在马路中间
On a road.
没费多大劲就找到了
Wasn't even that hard to find.
真是太棒了!
This is so amazing!
对啊!
I know!
你想拍张照吗?
You want to get a picture?
我不止要拍照
I want more than a picture.
我还要进去
I want to go in.
这个 我也想 不过他们不会肯的
Well, so do I, but they'll never let us.
你就是靠这态度追到Penny的?
Is that the attitude that helped you get Penny?
不是 但我又没有三年的时间
No, but I don't have three years
来让那扇大门觉得对不起我
to make that gate feel sorry for me.
呃 那里有个传话扬声器
Uh, there's a speaker box.
开上前去 按下按键 看看会怎么样
Drive up, push the button, and let's see what happens.
好吧 没错
Okay, yeah.
试试又有何妨?
What do we have to lose?
我有点紧张
I'm a little nervous.
那就克服它
Well, get over it.
遇到这种情况 关键要自信
Confidence is key in these situations.
说得对
Right.
你按了... 你是疯了吗?!
You pushed it... are you out of your mind?!
需要帮忙吗?
May I help you?
呃...
Um...
呃... 我们没有预约
Uh, uh... we don't have an appointment,
也... 也不该来这
and... and we don't belong here,
但我们... 我们是狂热粉丝
but we... we're, like, crazy-big fans.
我是说...
I mean...
"为'星球大战'而狂"的狂热
"crazy for Star Wars" crazy,
而不是那种背着一袋胶带的疯狂
not crazy like we have a backpack full of duct tape,
虽然我们的确有个背包
although we do have a backpack
但你真的不会想打开看的
that you really don't want to look in.
你搞砸了
You're blowing it.
我们想见乔治·卢卡斯
We want to meet George Lucas
做他的朋友 陪他玩!
and become his friends and play with him!
喂?
Hello?
扬声器坏了 进来吧
This speaker's not working, just pull up.
这才是正确的打开方式
And that's how it's done.
好的 我们已经闯过了第一关
All right, we've defeated the first challenge.
现在我们要鼓起勇气
Now we must steel ourselves to face the monster
打败守门的怪兽
who defends the gate.
我们只是要保安给我们放行而已
We're trying to get past a security guard,
塞尔达传说 游戏主人公
不是要解救塞尔达
not rescue Zelda.
我觉得你的想象力确实需要解救
I think what really needs to be rescued is your sense of whimsy,
不过任务得一个一个接
but one quest at a time.
所以我们的计划是?
So what's the plan?
呃 我只是想实话实说
Uh, I'm just gonna be honest with the guy.
那我们就进不去啦
Honesty will never get us in.
好吧 那你的计划是?
Well, what's your plan?
我计划是 假定里面有一个医务室
All right, my plan is predicated on the assumption
而你正好被刺伤了
that they have a nurse's office
这样我们就能名正言顺的进去了
and your willingness to be lightly stabbed.
你们是来找谁的?
Who are you here to see?
呃 我就跟你实话实说吧
Uh, I'm just gonna tell you the truth.
噢 一剑杀了我吧
Oh, you are killing me.
我们没有预约
We don't have an appointment.
我... 我们只是Lucas先生的粉丝
We... we're just fans of Mr. Lucas's work,
想来碰碰运气
and we thought we'd take a shot
进去四处转一转什么的
and see if we could get in and look around.
对不起两位 你们这种情况我见多了
Sorry, guys, we get this a lot.
不能让你们进去
Can't let you in.
如果我告诉你 我就尤达的配音呢?
What if I told you that I was the voice of Yoda?
这儿有个录音 我必须参加
A recording session I must attend.
对不起 别听他的
I'm sorry, don't listen to him.
我们其实是物理学家
We're actually physicists.
我们今天在伯克利有一场演讲
We're giving a lecture at Berkeley later today.
我们只是... 想打发一下时间罢了
We just... we had some time to kill.
呃 你们看上去像是好人
Hey, listen, you seem like decent guys.
但还是不能让你们进
I can't let you in,
不过我有些帽子和T恤 可以送给你们
but I got some hats and T-shirts I can give you.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much.
看见了吧?
See?
也许诚实才是最...
Maybe honesty is the best...
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
挣脱压制者的束缚
Shedding the yoke of my oppressors,
你这个愚蠢 短视的可怜人
you blind, sad little man.
别动!
Don't move!
代码 A-A-23 A-A-23
Code A-A-23, A-A-23.
收到
Copy.
我看到庄园了 Leonard!
I can see the ranch, Leonard!
噢 田园风 太可爱了!
Oh, it's rustic, it's lovely!
我想拍张照 但是他们都在追我
I'd take a picture, but people are chasing me.
我一定能进去...
I'm gonna make it...
我一定能进去!
I'm gonna make it!
他们有泰瑟枪 但他们不敢用...
They have Tasers, but they wouldn't dare use...
加油 Raj
Come on, Raj.
你就是乒乓界的金刚!
You are the King Kong of Ping-Pong!
即乒乓球
你就是桌上网球的最强杀手!
You are the menace of table tennis!
干掉她 因为我想不出第三个押韵了
Put her away, 'cause I don't have a third one.
好的! 太棒了!
Yes! Yes!
Rajesh得8分 Penny得4分
Rajesh eight, Penny four.
真抱歉 他打的太好了
Sorry, he's really good.
嘿 Raj
Hey, Raj.
如果Howard守不住时光机
if Howard can't keep the TARDIS,
那把它放在你家里 该有多棒?
how great would it look at your place?
什么?
What?
对啊 你说什么?
Yeah, what?
我不是很了解"神奇博士"
I don't know much about Doctor Who,
但是如果 呃 把这东西放到你家
but if, um, you were to put this
用作前门 把后面拆掉
right outside your front door and open up the back,
就会感觉是 你整个房子都在
it would be like your entire apartment was
时光机里面
the inside of the TARDIS,
是不是酷毙了
which is pretty cool
因为在剧情里 这时光机的内部空间
'cause on the show, the inside of the TARDIS
比外边的世界大多了
is bigger than the outside.
我重申一下 我也不是太了解"神奇博士"
But then again, I don't know much about Doctor Who.
别听她的
Don't listen to her.
你和我交情都这么久了... 我们就像兄弟一样
You and I go way back... we're like brothers.
我们是兄弟 兄弟
We are. We are.
噢 不!
Oh, no!
发球弱爆了!
What a terrible serve!
对不起 兄弟
Sorry, brother.
8比5 这太扯淡了
Eight-five. This is ridiculous.
我要换一个选手
I want a new champion.
Amy 你说你会发球 是认真的吗?
Amy, were you serious about being able to serve?
呃 我很久不打了
Uh, it...it's been a long time.
我不知道
I don't know.
我可能已经很迟钝了
I'm probably pretty rusty.
哇喔
Wow.
就是她了!
She's my champion!
好吧 既然你能换人 那我也要换
Well, if you can switch champions, so can I.
我要Raj 嘿
I want Raj. Hey.
行了 得了吧 好像你在乎似的
Oh, come on, like you even care.
我当然在乎!
I care!
呃 等等 我确实不在乎 祝你好运 Raj
Oh, wait, no, I don't. Good luck, Raj.
你知道吗 我以为我们的友情会更重要
You know, I thought our friendship meant more to you.
我也这么认为
So did I.
你觉得他们会报警吗?
Do you think they're gonna call the police?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许他们会叫一个帝国军官来
Maybe they'll call Imperial Officers to take us
送我们去死星上蹲监狱
to a holding cell on the Death Star.
呃 我觉得这还够不上帝国军官这种级别
Oh, I think that's below the pay grade of an Imperial Officer.
暴风部队才是...
Stormtroopers are really the ones who...
噢 闭嘴
Oh, shut up.
他说得对
He's right.
呃 暴风部队才同时拥有步兵
Uh, Stormtroopers actually combine both the function
和军事警察局的职能
of infantry and military police.
啊哈 我通常都不发火
Uh-huh, I'm normally very nice,
但是你也给我闭嘴
but you shut up, too.
所以...
So...
你犯什么事了?
what are you in for?
说实话 我只想见Lucas先生一面 对他说声谢谢
Honestly, I just wanted to meet Mr. Lucas and say thank you.
你知道的 在我长大成人的过程中 那些电影对我意义非凡
You know, growing up, the movies had such an impact on my life.
我一直不知道自己属于哪里
I never really fit in anywhere.
直到发现了他所创造的世界
Till I discovered the worlds he created
我才找到了自己的归属感
and finally found a place where I belong.
那你怎么会在这儿?
But why are you here?
噢 我 呃... 我翻了一道篱笆
Oh, I, uh... I hopped a fence,
他们在雕塑馆里抓到了我
and they caught me in the sculpture gallery
当时我正在和楚巴卡雕塑亲热
making out with a Chewbacca statue.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
Leonard啊
Leonard,
他们有一个雕塑馆
they have a sculpture gallery.
好了 我跟上级汇报过了
All right, I talked to my supervisor,
得给你个警告 不过你可以走了
and we're gonna let you go with a warning.
要是你敢再回来
But if you ever come back,
我们就报警 告你了
we will call the police and press charges.
明白
We understand.
多谢您了
Thank you so much.
那我呢?
Uh, what about me?
你给我老实呆着 嘟嘴哥
No, you're not going anywhere, kissy face.
走吧
Let's go.
我得拍张你的照片 贴在安检门口
I have to take your picture to post at the guard gate.
拍照的事
Uh, one question
我有个小问题
about that picture.
星战导演
能不能和George Lucas合照呢?
Can it be with George Lucas?
哎哟哟 你好暴躁呢
Ooh, grumpy you are.
好 这就是决胜局了
Okay, this is the match that decides it all.
先拿到11分的算赢
First to 11 wins.
每五分 换发球权
Serve switches every five points.
告知你一下 一开始
And just so you know, when this started,
我本来只想把时光机放在某个隐蔽的角落
I was going to put the TARDIS in a discreet corner of the house,
不过既然你逼我做坏人 现在我要把它
but I've since turned mean, and now it's going
放在客厅正中央
right in the middle of the living room
下面再加一个旋转展示台 上面挂个大牌子"去死吧"
on a rotating platform with a sign that says "suck it."
游戏开始
Game on.
不过...
Except...
Raj会赢的
Raj is gonna win.
对吧 Raj?
Isn't that right, Raj?
对 不过 她发球确实挺厉害的
Uh, yeah, I mean, her serve was pretty good.
别怂 跟她玩心理战
Come on, get in her head.
气势上压倒她
Be intimidating.
好...
Okay, uh...
你就等死吧 婊子!
I'm gonna own you, bitch!
喂! 嘿!
Whoa! Hey!
这话说得太狠了
That's not nice.
开始比吧
Let's just play.
一比零
One-zero.
二比零
Two.
三比零
Three.
四比零
Four.
五比零
Five-nothing.
我说
Wait,
你玩的是羽毛球
did you play badminton
还是郁闷球?
or sad-minton?
别听他的... 她也就会发球
Don't listen to him... all she's got is a serve.
你快塞上卫生棉条 把她打倒
Now, grab a fresh tampon and put her away.
啥...?
Wha...?
这样说就可以?
A... And that's not offensive?
底线到底在哪啊?
Where's the line?
purse专指女士钱包 此处为了句意 加了粉色
在你的粉色小钱包里 快打
It's in your purse. Play.
一比五
One-five.
二比五
Two-five.
三比五
Three-five.
四比五
Four-five.
五平!
Five-five!
六
Six.
七
Seven.
八 九
Eight. Nine.
十比五!
Ten-five!
六
Six.
七
Seven.
八
Eight.
九
Nine.
十平!
Ten-ten!
刚刚真是惊险刺激的四十秒
Well, that was an exciting 40 seconds.
确实 现在该你发球了
It was, and now the serve is back to you,
游戏就要结束了
and the game is over.
我说 Amy啊...
You know, Amy, I, uh...
不知道Sheldon看到你房间里
can't help but wonder how Sheldon would react
有个时光机会怎么想呢
if the TARDIS was at your place.
别听她的 快发球
Don't listen to her, just hit the ball.
你继续说
Keep talking.
要是这还不能让他进你卧室
If this doesn't get him into your bedroom,
我真不知道还能怎么办了
nothing will.
你还生我的气吗?
Are you still mad at me?
对啊 我们错过了讲座 差点被逮捕了
Yes, we missed our lecture, we were almost arrested,
你害得我被关起来了
and you got me locked in a room with a man
还和一个对伍基人雕塑强行舌吻的人关在一起
who forced his tongue down the throat of a stuffed Wookiee.
天呐 某些人只能看到半杯空 看不到半杯满
Boy, some people are just glass-half-empty.
这整个就是空的啊 Sheldon
The glass is empty, Sheldon.
一滴水都没
It's completely empty.
你要是把这杯给一个快渴死的人
If you gave that glass to a man who was dying of thirst,
他就死了 知道为什么吗?
he would be dead, do you know why?
我回答之前先问一下 他吸烟吗?
Before I answer, was he a smoker?
我觉得你得换一个角度看事情
I think you're looking at this all wrong.
好吧 那你说 我该怎么看
Fine, then tell me how I should be looking at it.
我们不仅开到了"天行者庄园" 还进了门
Well, not only did we go to Skywalker Ranch, we got in.
我们圈子里 这可是头一次
No one we know can say that.
而且 你不是一直嫌我烦吗
And for all the times you find me irritating,
今天你目睹了我被泰瑟枪电倒的景象
today you got to watch someone shoot me with a Taser.
这我确实看得很开心
That part was pretty good.
是吧?
See?
你确实抖动了好一阵
You did flop around a lot.
我就暂且信了吧
I'll take your word for it.
当时我在竭尽全力不让自己大便失禁
I was too busy trying not to defecate.
知道吗 他们把我们押送到
You know, when they were escorting us
拘留室的路上 我透过某扇门
to the detaining room, I looked through a door,
应该是看到了一个装着
and I'm pretty sure I saw a display case
约柜: 传说中遗失的圣物
约柜的展示柜
with the Ark of the Covenant.
- 太棒了  - 是啊
- That's amazing.  - I know.
星战中的怪物
我看到赫特人贾巴骑着摩托车路过
And I saw Jabba the Hutt riding by on a motorcycle.
不过是我被电倒之后看到的
Although that was right after the Tasing,
也不知道是不是幻觉
so who can say for sure?
我... 想 这也算是一次大冒险了
I... I guess this could count as an adventure.
确实是
It was.
虽然我们不能再回去了
And even though we're not allowed back there,
但是他们夺不走我们今天的记忆
they can never take today away from us.
不过好像夺走了我的嗅觉
Unlike my sense of smell,
被电倒之后 我就闻不到东西了
which hasn't returned since the Tasing.
嗯 什么味道都没有
No, I got nothing.
戴立克是博士的机器人对头
Amy 戴立克追的我好紧!
Amy, the Daleks are right on my tail!
快 重设时间电路
Quick, we need to reset the time circuits.
不好 我把音速起子落下了
Oh, no, I left my sonic screwdriver behind.
当时真该多想想
Really should have thought this through.
这集梗有点多 基本上都做了注释 感谢一下翻译们的尽力
但也可能有不完美的地方 如果观众发现有梗或翻译错误
请新浪微博@圣城SCG字幕组
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 凤梨酥
翻译: 酱油影 奥利奥 夏至未寒 UU养了只狐狸叫查理
校对: UU养了只狐狸叫查理